#### **IRFAN KHAN**

0

Nowshera KPK, Pakistan



+923138060977



irfankhan4552@vahoo.com



15/02/1993



Pakistani



https://www.linkedin.com/in/irfan-khan-01b8a4163/

#### **Research Interest**

During my four year degree, studying basics of Civil Engineering, I got profoundly interested in Structural Engineering with an inspiration of further studies in the field. I have developed a particular interest in the computational modelling of masonry structures for seismic loading, on which I have carried out my MSc research work. I would like to advance my research further, through PhD study under the supervision of an expert at a remarkable institution.

# **Education**

Oct 2017 - Mar 2020

# **MSc in Structural Engineering**

University of Engineering and Technology Peshawar, Pakistan

■ **Thesis Title:** Computational Seismic Analysis of Dry-Stack Block Masonry

Oct 2013 – Jul 2017

# **BSc in Civil Engineering**

University of Engineering and Technology Peshawar, Pakistan

• Final Year Project: Analysis and Design of Sandwiched Concrete Insulated Panel (SCIP) Buildings using SAP2000

Sep 2010 – May 2012

#### **Higher Secondary School Certificate**

Islamia College Peshawar, Pakistan

Pre-Engineering

# **Research Experience**

Sep 2019 – May 2020

#### **Research Associate**

University of Engineering and Technology Peshawar, Pakistan Responsibilities:

- Literature study on "Seismic Performance Evaluation of Adobe Structures"
- Casting samples using "Adobe Bricks" for prism and triplet tests
- Testing of samples according to ASTM
- Construction of Adobe Walls for Quasi-Static Tests and their Computational Modelling
- Guidance and assessment of Bachelor students on their Final Year Projects

Jan 2019 - Sep 2019

# **Research Associate**

University of Engineering and Technology Peshawar, Pakistan

#### Responsibilities:

- Supervision of construction of half and full scale rooms
- Technical Assistance on construction activities
- Laboratory Testing of Materials
- Calculations for Half Scale Model for Shake Table Test

Mar 2018 - Dec 2018

#### **Research Assistant**

University of Engineering and Technology Peshawar, Pakistan Responsibilities:

 Modelling and Analysis of Reinforced Concrete Sandwich Panels (RCSPs) using SAP2000 for Blast Load

Oct 2017 - Mar 2018

# **Teaching Assistant – Geotechnical Engineering**

University of Engineering and Technology Peshawar, Pakistan

# **Field Experience**

Jun 2020 - Date

## Assistant Resident Engineer – Earthfill Dam

Consulting Associates Peshawar, Pakistan

- Quality Control of materials on site
- Inspection of formwork, steel reinforcement and concrete pouring
- Verification of lab and field tests according to standards
- Monthly Progress Report

Oct 2017 - Feb 2018

# Trainee Engineer

Khyber Geotechnical Services Peshawar, Pakistan Responsibilities:

- On-site tests (SPT, CPT, Plate Load and Vane Shear Tests)
- Lab tests (Sieve Analysis, Atterberg Limits and Consolidation Tests)
- Geological Studies using ArcGIS
- Preparation of Geotechnical Reports

### **Publications**

- Khan, I. Gul, A. Shahzada, K. Khan, N.A. Rehman, F. Ullah, Q.S. Kattak, M.A. (2021), Computational Seismic Analysis of Dry-Stack Block Masonry Wall, *Civil Engineering Journal* 7(3).
- Ali, M. Rehman, G. Ahmad, K. Khan, S.W. Khan, I. Ullah, A. Shahzada, K. Analysis of the effect of phase change material on indoor temperature in subtropical climate region, *International Journal of Solar Thermal Vacuum Engineering 1, Issue 1* (2020).

### **Short Courses / Seminars**

Oct 30, 2019

Groundwater Resource Management in Pakistan: Issues and Options

Nov 10, 2018 Administrative Office Management

# Certification

Jul 28, 2017 Certificate of Participation, Poster Competition: Institution of

Civil Engineers

Nov 16 & 17, 2016 Certificate of Participation; Invention to Innovation Summit

Nov 27, 2015 Certificate of Merit; KP Wooden Bridge Design Competition

2015

# Skills

Software skills MS Office, MATLAB, AutoCAD, Civil 3D, SAP2000, ETABS,

Primavera P6, ANSYS, ABAQUS

Language skills Pashto / Native, English / Fluent, Urdu / Fluent

# **Hobbies**

Teaching

Newspaper Reading

Technical Documentaries

# References

Dr. Khan Shahzada

Professor, Civil Engineering Department, UET Peshawar

Email: khanshahzada@uetpeshawar.edu.pk

Dr. Mohammad Adil

Assistant Professor, Civil Engineering Department, UET Peshawar

Email: adil@uetpeshawar.edu.pk